A Guide to the Lyman Creighton Craig papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA134
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Professional correspondence, 1950 1952-1974; 2
  - N-No (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Nerath, F., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Neuberger, A., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 8)
      [See also under: Robinson, F.A. in box no 12].
    - Neurath, H., 1952 1955 1971; 11 letters (Box 8, Folder 8)
      Primarily about Meeting: 1955 May Indianapolis, Ind. insulin conference. Indications are Dr. Craig participates in discussion.
    - Newburgh, R.W., 1968; 3 letters (Box 8, Folder 8)
      Includes 1968 pamphlet on graduate opportunities in biochemistry and biophysics.
    - New England Institute, 1966-1972; 12 letters (Box 8, Folder 8)
      Includes lectures: 1969 Oct. Dr. Craig distinguished visitor for postdoctoral program. Delivers talks to students and staff on "current laboratory work".
    - Newton, G., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - New York Academy of Sciences. Dr. Craig member until 1958, 12 letters (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - New York State Society for Medical Research. Member of, 1954-1955; 4 letters (Box 8, Folder 8)
      Includes 1954-55 membership card.
    - Niemann, C., 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Niu, M.C., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Nobel Committee, 1953 1963-1964; 6 letters (Box 8, Folder 8)
      Recommendations for V. du Vigneaud; C.H. Li and S. Moore and W. Stein for Nobel prize.
    - Nodelman, N., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Norelco Reporter, 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Norman, P.S. At RIMR 1954-1956. Curriculum vitae with bibliography and promotion recommendation for, 3 letters (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - National Academy of Sciences (113), 1953-1973; 2 folders
    1951 elected member of; attends meetings and delivers papers. Indications are from 1963-1965 L.C. Craig, Secretary of biochemistry section of NAS.
    - 1953-1961 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Special interest items: in chronological order. Report of NAS Committee on Loyalty in relation to government support of unclassified research with Sherman Adams reply
      - Meeting: NYC Columbia University NAS meeting. Craig, Hausman and Weisiger "The nature of bacitracin, 1954 November 8-10
        Includes copies of paper and abstract and listing of all abstracts presented.
      - Meeting: Washington, DC NAS meeting. Craig and King "Some experiments with fractionation by partial dialysis", 1956 November 8-10
        Includes copies of paper and abstract and meeting announcement.
      - NAS membership recommendation for W. Stein and S. Moore
      - Meeting: Washington, DC NAS conference on sulfur compounds. King and Craig "Counter-current distribution studies with proteins", 1957 November
      - Meeting: Washington, DC NAS conference on chemical compounds of certified high purity. (Sponsored by NRC-NSF), 1959 June 22-23
        Craig participant in Group II, General discussion II June 23. Includes conference agenda, list of participants, tentative assignments for group discussion and unconfirmed report of conference with Craig reply and bound copy of report.
      - Photocopy of Science 131 (1960) 1785-1790 "The Tercentenary of the Royal Society" Summer 1960. No indication Craig attends
    - 1962-1973 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Meeting: Washington, DC NAS 100 annual meeting, 1963 April 22-24
        Craig and Guidotti "The dialysis behavior of peptides and proteins which associate" Includes typescript of paper and abstract and copy of minutes by L.C. Craig of biochemistry section meeting on April 22.
      - 4 items about President Kennedy's death
      - Meeting: Washington, DC 101st annual meeting. Program of scientific demonstrations and exhibits, 1964 April 27-28
        Craig demonstrates "Separations by extraction". Includes letter of commendation from F. Seitz on exhibit and minutes of Apr 27 meeting of biochemistry section of NAS.
      - Meeting: minutes of meeting of biochemistry section of NAS, 1965 April 27
      - Craig letters of congratulations to newly elected members of NAS
      - Report of ad hoc committee on policy with respect to studies of genetic quality, 1970
  - Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences (PNAS)., 54 letters (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Deals primarily with submitting mss for publication by Craig and others. Includes duplicated material.
  - National Academy of Sciences-National Research Council (Quartermaster Research) (113) (NAS-NRC Quartermaster Research), 2 folders (Box 9)
    Dr. Craig member of the committee on pioneering research of the NRC advisory board on Quartermaster Research and Development and several of its subcommittees. Attends meeting and delivers papers at some. Includes agendas; minutes of meetings; membership lists; programs; and numerous bi-monthly reports and 1965 annual report.
    - 1953-1959 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Special interest items
        Copy of statement of policy and organization of advisory board on Quartermaster Research and Development Committees. Policy is to furnish scientific and technical advisory service. Includes security questionnaire (handwritten) for Craig.
      - Meeting: Natick, Mass. Advisory Board, 1955 February 11
      - Meeting: Natick, Mass. Subcommittee on chemistry of flavor and odor conference. Dr. Craig serves on this subcommittee, 1955 December 15
        Includes copies of summary of special report prepared by Craig, Hitchcock, Walling (summary by Walling) [See also under: Walling, C. in box no. 14].
      - Meeting: Natick, Mass. Subcommittee on protein research meeting. Dr. Craig member of this subcommittee, 1956 January 20
      - Meeting: Natick, Mass. Conference on advances in the chemistry of naturally occurring organic sulfur compounds, 1956 October 10-11
        Includes newsletter and what appears to be handwritten notes.
      - Meeting: Natick, Mass. Second organic conference on basic sugar, steroid and polyterpene chemistry, 1958 November 6-7
        Includes handwritten notes on back of program.
      - Meeting: Natick, Mass. Committee on pioneering research meeting. Craig "The chemistry of bacitracin and some of its implications in protein chemistry" (Continued on next page), 1959 October 15-16
    - 1960-1962 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Meeting: Natick, Mass. Quartermaster Research Industry Day, 1960 May 19
        Includes handwritten notes.
      - Advisory Board on Quartermaster Research and Development pamphlet on organization and operation, 1960 July
      - Meeting: Natick, Mass. Fourth organic chemistry conference on the chemistry of heterocyclic compounds and alkaloids, 1960 October 13-14
      - Recommendations for T.P. King, A. Crestfield and H. Tallan
  - NAS-NRC (Quartermaster research), 1963-1972; 59 letters (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Special interest items, 1961-1965
      Includes 1961-1962 and 1963, 1964, 1965 Pioneering Research Division publications and review of Stern and Karger and Elving grant applications for NAS-NRC, US Army research office (Durham).
    - Meeting: Natick, Mass. 11th annual conference on organic chemistry jointly by Pioneering Research Laboratory, US Array Natick Laboratories/Committee, on Pioneering Research NRC, 1967 October 12-13
      Indications Dr. Craig attends. Includes preliminary program.
    - Recommendations for R. Hill, E. Shaw and M. Printz
  - NAS-NRC Russian scientists visitors, 1958-1973; 59 letters (Box 10, Folder 2)
    Under agreement on the exchange of scientists between the NAS of the USA and the Academy of Science of the USSR Russian scientists visit Dr. Craig's laboratory. Includes biographical data on visiting scientists; duplicated copy of agreement; also includes invitations to symposiums in Russia.
    Arranged in chronological order: Administrative arrangements for visits.
  - National Science Foundation (NSF), 1957-1974; 2 folders, 47 letters (Box 10)
    Deals primarily with reviewing grant proposals FOR NSF; in most instances proposals included.
    - 1957-1972 June (Box 10, Folder 3)
      Special interest item: 1958 April-May Dr. Craig assisted in planning and preparing the NSF exhibit on "Phase equilibria" in the Int'l Science Hall at the Brussels' World's Fair. Dr. Craig's counter current extraction apparatus displayed.
    - 1972 September-1974 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - O (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Oberlin College, 1967 October 25; 8 letters
      Lecture: 1967 Oct 25 Oberlin, Ohio, Chemistry seminar program "The key role of separation and purification in organic chemistry". Includes handwritten letter by son-in-law Dave (on Oberlin faculty) about lecture title.
    - O'Brien, J. Recommendations for, 2 letters
    - Ochoa, S. Acceptances to invitations at NYU medical school, 4 letters
    - Ofner, P., 1 letter
    - O'hern, R.S., 1 letter
    - Oke, T.O., 2 letters
    - Oncley, J.L., 1953-1954 1963; 7 letters
      Includes 1954 Feb 24 Harvard University seminar "Some structural studies with naturally occurring peptides.
    - Ondetti, M.A., 1 letter
    - O'Neal, C.H., 2 letters
    - Orekhovitch, V., 1 letter
    - Oser, B., 1 letter
    - Otteson, M., 2 letters
      About Lindestrm-Lang endowment fund.
    - Overberger, C.G., 1953 1955; 8 letters
      Meetings: 1953 New York ACS meeting: papers from Craig laboratory: L.R. Weisinger and L.C. Craig "Structural studies with bacitracin"; W. Hausmann "Fatty acids in polymixin B and polypeptin"; E.J. Harfenist "Differences in the quantitative amino acid composition of insulins.
      Includes abstracts. Also indicates Dr. Craig on program planning committee for 1955 ACS NY section lecture series.
  - P-Pe (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Page, I.H. At RIMR 1931-1937, 1953 1963-1965; 9 letters
      Includes congratulations on Dr. Page winning Gairdner foundation award; reprint of Page editorial "Needed-Nat'l Academy of Medicine" and copy of Page's "Membership in a Nat'l Academy of Medicine" with Craig comments.
    - Pan, S.C., 2 letters
    - Panse, G.T., 2 letters
    - Parimoo, P., 6 letters
    - Parsons, S.M. Curriculum vitae with bibliography, 3 letters
    - Parthasarathy, P.C., 1 letter
    - Passano Foundation. 1945-1972 winners of Passano award, 2 letters
    - Patchornik, A. Curriculum vitae with bibliography, 4 letters
      Includes promotion recommendation for.
    - Patil, K.M., 2 letters
    - Paul, I.C., 2 letters
    - Peller, J.A., 1 letter
    - Penndorf, P.R. Dr. Craig's views on non-use of automatic sprinklers for new Tower building, 1 letter
    - Pentex Inc., 1 letter
    - Pergamon Press, 1960; 17 letters
      Manuscripts: Deals primarily with Craig chapters "Partition" and "Fractionation and characterization by dialysis". Published in 1960 by Pergamon [See also under: Mss 1960 in box no. 26].
    - Perlmann, G.E., 1955 1969; 6 letters
      Correspondence between W. Stein and D.W. Bronk and 1 item F. Seitz concerning.
      Includes curriculum vitae with bibliography.
    - Perry, E.S.
      [See under: Interscience Publishers in box no. 16].
    - Perutz, M.F., 2 letters
    - Peterson, R.E., 1 letter
  - Pe-Pu (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Petersson, G.A. RU lecturer, 4 letters (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Includes curriculum vitae and Cory and Petersson ms "on strategic bonds".
    - Petra, P.H., 4 letters (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Pettinato, F.A., 2 letters (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Pfaffmann, C. RU Professor, 3 letters (Box 11, Folder 3)
      About conference on biological and behavioral sciences at RU.
      Includes program. Dr. Craig invited but does not attend.
    - Philips, F.S. Lecture: 1956 Dec 5 NYC, Sloan Kettering lecture series "Some experiments dealing with fractionation by dialysis", 1956 December 5; 2 letters (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Phillips, M.C., 2 letters (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Phillips, T.A., 1952 1955; 4 letters (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Meetings: About 1952 and 1955 Ciba symposiums Craig attends.
    - Pickering, B.T., 1 letter (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Pierce-Chase, C., 1 letter (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Pines, E. Curriculum vitae, 2 letters (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Pinkalla, H.A., 5 letters (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Pittsburgh Coke and Chemical Co., 2 letters (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Plaut, G.W.E., 1966 October 10; 3 letters (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Lectures: 1966 Oct 10. New Brunswick, N.J. Rutgers University Medical school, Dept of biochemistry, afternoon to medical students "The use of countercurrent extraction processes in biochemistry" and evening "The use of simple dialysis as a tool in biochemistry".
    - Plum, Fred, 2 letters (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Recommendations to chairmanship Cornell University Medical College, Biochemistry Dept (Professor du Vigneaud successor) for A. Kornberg, H. Rasmussen, W. McElroy, P. Handler, G. Brown and F. Carpenter.
    - Porath, J., 1952-1954 1961-1969; 15 letters (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Professional correspondence between colleagues. Includes appraisal of Porath's contribution to biochemistry along with S. Moore, W.H. Stein, H.G. Kunkel, L.G. Longsworth.
    - Porter, K.R., 1 letter (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Congratulations on Porter election to NAS.
    - Porter, R.R., 2 letters (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Portugal, F.H., 2 letters (Box 11, Folder 3)
      About "history of nucleic acid research" Portugal project with Craig's account on development of use of countercurrent distribution technique.
    - Poulos, S.J., 2 letters (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Powers, J.E., 2 letters (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Powers, J.L., 2 letters (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Review of 2 mss for publication in J American Pharmaceutical Assoc.
    - Prasad, P.N. Curriculum vitae, 3 letters (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Preparative Biochemistry, 2 letters (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Pressman, B.C., 3 letters (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Princeton University, 2 letters (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Ptak, M., 2 letters (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Pulley, A.O., 2 letters (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Purdue University, 1 letter (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Purdy, R.H., 3 letters (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Paladini, A.C. (167) At RU, 1947-1952 1953-1956 1962-1973 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Includes: Meeting: 1966 Nov 26-Dec Buenos Aires, 7th Panamerican congress of pharmacy and biochemistry. Includes copy of presentation "The continuing importance of selective separations in biochemistry" and round table discussion Craig "The use of antibiotic peptides as models for the study of inter and intra molecular forces in proteins". Includes program (in Spanish) of round table discussion. Also includes P. Siekevitz letter to Science "Displaced Argentine scientists" and Footnote to the Argentine crisis: a letter from American scientists and review of Dellachia and Santome-Forge grant application.
  - Pelletier, Wm. At RI 1951-1962, 1957-1971; 65 letters (Box 11, Folder 5)
    Includes curriculum vitae with bibliography and nomination for ASBC membership for.
  - Post, Otto. At RI 1924-1952 (technician), 1952-1956 1961-1972; 44 letters (Box 11, Folder 6)
    Correspondence primarily about Dr. Craig's counter-current distribution instrument. Includes sketches of present equipment and contemplated equipment; H.P. Post catalog (Post manufactures CCD instrument; Dr. Craig inventor) and at 1964 NAS centennial meeting Dr. Craig exhibits a CCD instrument. Also includes recommendations for Post and Post employee, Walter Albert. In 1966 Dr. Craig recipient of Fisher award for development of CCD technique. [See also under: CCD in box no. 15 and Fisher award in box no. 1].
  - Printz, Morton. AT RU 1965-1972, 1964-1974; 83 letters (Box 11, Folder 7)
    Includes numerous employment and promotion recommendations for; nomination for ASBC membership for; also includes employment recommendations for H.C. Chen and Anne D. Gounaris with curriculum vitae; 1967 Spring copy of M. Printz "Summary of recent research activities".
  - Q (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Quikfit and Quartz Ltd., 1 letter
    - Qureshi, I.H. Curriculum vitae, 3 letters
  - R-Rod (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Rahman, A. Curriculum vitae, 2 letters
    - Rajewsky, K., 2 letters
    - Ramachandran, G.N., 2 letters
    - Ramachandran, L.K., 2 letters
    - Ramirez, F., 5 letters
    - Ramos, M. Deferrment recommendation for, 1 letter
    - Randall, E.W., 2 letters
    - Rao, N.A., 2 letters
    - Rasmussen, P.S., 2 letters
    - Ratner, L., 2 letters
    - Ray, A. Curriculum vitae, 1 letter
    - Ray, D.K. Bibliography and handwritten note by S. Moore, 1 letter
    - Raymond, S., 2 letters
      [See also under: CCD in box no. 15].
    - Reeves, H.S., 1 letter
    - Reeves, W.G., 2 letters
    - Regan, T.M., 1 letter
    - Regna, P. Correspondence between friendly colleagues, 1954-1955 1965; 7 letters
    - Reid, E.E., 5 letters
      Includes comments on Reid work for honorary degree and letter of congratulations on receipt.
    - Reilley, C.N., 2 letters
    - Ressler, C., 6 letters
      Includes employment recommendation for.
    - Reyerson, L.H., 2 letters
    - Richards, F.M., 2 letters
    - Richardson, R., 2 letters
    - Rigakos, J.N., 1965 1974; 2 letters
    - Riggsby, E.D., 1 letter
    - Rimon, A. At RU 1967-1968. Bibliography and Rimon progress report, 14 letters
    - Rimberg, R.E., 1 letter
    - Riniker, B., 1964 1966 1970-1971; 8 letters
      Includes scientific exchange on thin film dialysis studies with ACTH peptides.
    - Rittenberg, M.S., 2 letters
    - Robbins, K.C., 2 letters
    - Robbins, R., 1 letter
    - Roberts, Joan E. Curriculum vitae, 3 letters
    - Roberts, John D. Primarily arrangements for Roberts 1973 RU lecture, 18 letters
    - Robinson, F.A., 4 letters
      Includes report on the purity studies by CCD of insulin sample.
    - Rodriguez, J.L. Suggestions on CCD model purchase, 3 letters
  - Rog-Ry (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Roger, Muriel. At RU 1956 -. (Faculty), 13 letters (Box 12, Folder 3)
      Concerning Dr. Roger's possible promotion. Includes biographical material and Roger et al available reprints.
    - Rohm and Haas Co., 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Roman, R.G., 3 letters (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Roncari, G. At RU 1963-1965, 18 letters (Box 12, Folder 3)
      [See also under: Hoffmann-LaRoche in box no. 6].
    - Rose, A., 1955 1972; 4 letters (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Rosen, P. At RU 1959 -. Biographical material for employment of, 7 letters (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Rosen, S.W., 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Rosenberg, R.M., 4 letters (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Ross, S.D., 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Rossini, F.D., 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Rothbart, H.D., 3 letters (Box 12, Folder 3)
      Review of Rothbart et al ms with ms.
    - Rounds, T.C. Curriculum vitae, 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Roy, B.P. Curriculum vitae, 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Roy, T.B.G., 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Rupe, C.E., 3 letters (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Rupley, J.A., 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Ruyssen, R., 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Ryan, J.W., 3 letters (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Rycus, J.L., 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 3)
      Recommendation for J. Ramachandran.
  - Rasmussen, Howard. RU graduate student, 1958-1970; 50 letters (Box 12, Folder 4)
    Includes 1959 copy of presentation for Ph. D by Craig with convocation program and recommendations for and evaluation of grant proposal with proposal.
  - Rifkin, Daniel B. RU graduate student, 1964-1970; 21 letters (Box 12, Folder 5)
    Includes fellowship and other recommendations and 1964 annual report.
  - Ruttenberg, Michael. RU graduate student, 1961-1970; 65 letters (Box 12, Folder 6)
    Curriculum vitae with bibliography. Also includes recommendations for postdoctoral fellowship, medical school admission and others; evaluation of NIH grant application; 1963-1964 annual report on M. Ruttenberg progress f.
  - S-Sch (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Sacks, L.E., 4 letters
    - Saha, A., 2 letters
    - Said, S.I., 2 letters
    - Saint Louis University, 1 letter
    - Salah-Uddin, 2 letters
    - Salvin, S.B., 2 letters
    - Samuel, P., 2 letters
    - Sandoz Pharmaceutical Co., 12 letters
    - Sankar, D.V.S., 2 letters
    - Saperstein, D. Curriculum vitae, 3 letters
    - Saravis, C.A., 3 letters
    - Sato, Y., 2 letters
    - Sawada, F., 1 letter
    - Sawai Man Singh Medical College, 2 letters
    - Schackman, H., 1953 1964-1966; 4 letters
    - Schaechter, M., 2 letters
    - Schaffer, N.K., 2 letters
    - Schally, A.V., 1963-1971; 23 letters
      Includes promotion recommendation for and typescript of Schally et al ms "Counter-current distribution as a tool for purification of hypothalmic hormones on a preparative scale" with Craig comments.
      [See also under: CCD in box no 15].
  - Sch-Sco (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Schapira, G., 4 letters
    - Scharoun, J.E., 2 letters
    - Schatz, A., 2 letters
    - Scheibel, E.C., 2 letters
    - Scheraga, H.A., 2 letters
    - Schmid, K., 2 letters
    - Schmidt, C.F., 2 letters
    - Schoenfeld, J. Medical school admission recommendation for, 2 letters
    - Schoenfeld, R.L. At RU 1958 - (Faculty), 1959 1969; 9 letters
      Promotion recommendations for with biographical material and bibliography. Includes 1959 Schoenfeld write up of MacNichol photomultiplyer unit.
    - Scholler, Dr., 2 letters
    - Schrager, G.R., 4 letters
    - Schroeder, W.A., 4 letters
    - Schwab, H. Lecture: 1953 Mar 25 NY Academy of Medicine, NY section of Soc Exp Biol Med symposium on diabetes mellitus "Structure of insulin", 1953 March 25; 2 letters
    - Schwarz, J., 2 letters
    - Schweitzer, G.K. Craig suggestion on purchasing CCD apparatus, 2 letters
    - Schwind, R.A., 2 letters
    - Schwyzer, R., 7 letters
    - Scoffone, E., 2 letters
    - Scozzie, J.A., 20 letters
      Includes biographical material.
  - Scr-Sl (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Scribner, B.H., 1967 November 1; 13 letters
      Includes: Lecture: 1967 Nov 1 Seattle, Wash. University of Washington. "Thin film dialysis".
    - Scull, S.G., 1956 April 15-19; 2 letters
      Meeting: About reservation for 1956 Apr 15-19 Atlantic City, NJ FASEB meeting.
    - Secondini, O., 2 letters
    - Seigle, R.L. Recommendations for medical school admission, 6 letters
    - Sela, M., 6 letters
    - Sen, C.P., 8 letters
      Review of Sen ms "Studies on CCD Part III. Effect of temperature on the distribution pattern of a solute between immiscible solvent phases. " Includes ms.
    - Separation Science, 1965-1969 1973; 16 letters
    - Shabarova, Zoe. Russian visitor, 1 letter
    - Shannon, J.A., 2 letters
    - Shaw, E.N., 4 letters
      Includes congratulations to Dr. Craig on Lasker award.
    - Sheehan, J.C., 7 letters
    - Sherwood, I.R., 1 letter
    - Shields, J.E., 5 letters
    - Shifrin, S., 1 letter
    - Shine, H.J., 2 letters
    - Siggia, S., 1 letter
    - Sigma Xi. On nominating committee, 1964-1965; 1 letter
    - Signer, R., 3 letters
    - Silaev, A.B., 2 letters
    - Silard, Dr., 1 letter
    - Simmonds, D.H., 2 letters
    - Simon, A.B., 4 letters
    - Skeggs, L.T., 1 letter
    - Slaunwhite, W.R., 2 letters
    - Slonimski, P., 2 letters
  - Sm-Sy (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Smalle, D.E., 3 letters (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Smith, C.R., 1 letter (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Smith, E.D., 2 letters (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Smith, E.L., 7 letters (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Smyth, D., 4 letters (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Snow, G.A., 1 letter (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Sober, H., 1 letter (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Sollner, Karl, 1962-1963 1970; 8 letters (Box 13, Folder 2)
      Includes: Lecture: 1962 May 16 Bethesda, Md. NIH physical biochemistry seminar "Improved membranes of graded porosities as simple highly selective tools for separation and characterization".
    - Sophianopoulos, A.J., 1 letter (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Spencer, Martin. RU graduate student, 13 letters (Box 13, Folder 2)
      Includes recommendations for.
    - Sperry, W.M., 1 letter (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Sprague, J.M., 4 letters (Box 13, Folder 2)